Guide to the Leo Lerman papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Topical Files, 1950s-1990s
  - Reagan, Nancy (Box 37)
  - Real People: Book Characters (Box 37)
  - Reed, Julia (Box 37)
  - Reinhardt, Max (Box 37)
  - Resnick, Regina (Box 37)
  - Research, Proposals, Ideas-- Fiction, (3 Folders) (Box 37)
  - Research, Proposals, Ideas-- General, (5 Folders) (Box 37)
  - Research-- Palladio (Box 37)
  - Rhys, Jean (Box 38)
  - Riddle, Clara (Box 38)
  - Roditi, Edouard (Box 38)
  - Rolo, Charles (Box 38)
  - Rosenbach, Abraham (Box 38)
  - Ross, Herbert and Nora (Box 38)
  - Roth, Phillip (Box 38)
  - Rugs (Box 38)
  - Runaways, (2 Folders) (Box 38)
  - Saal, Rollene (Box 38)
  - Saarinen, Aline (Box 38)
  - Saatchi, Charles and Doris (Box 38)
  - Schatski, Walter (Box 38)
  - School of American Ballet (Box 38)
  - Scott, Zachary, Ford, and Ruth (Box 38)
  - Sharaff, Irene (Box 38)
  - Shaw, Mark (Box 38)
  - Shells (Box 38)
  - Sheraton, Mimi (Box 38)
  - Shore, Jaye (Box 38)
  - Sills, Beverly (Box 38)
  - Simpson, Jeffrey (Box 38)
  - Singer, Norman (Box 38)
  - Sitwell Family (Box 38)
  - Skittles (Box 38)
  - Snapper, Elsa (Box 38)
  - Snow, Carmel (Box 38)
  - Society (Box 38)
  - Sonnenberg, Benjamin (Box 38)
  - Sondheim, Stephen (Box 38)
  - Sontag, Stephen (Box 38)
  - Speiser, Martha (Box 38)
  - Spinsters/"Bachelor Girl" (Box 38)
  - Spoons, Apostle (Box 38)
  - Staffordshire (Box 38)
  - Stamps (Box 38)
  - Stark, Freya (Box 38)
  - Strange, Mopsy (Box 38)
  - Straus, Dorothea (Box 38)
  - Stuart, Jan (Box 38)
  - Svinin, Paul (Box 38)
  - Swanson, Gloria (Box 38)
  - Stutz, Geraldine (Box 38)
  - Sze, Mai Mai (Box 38)
  - Talmey, Allene (Box 38)
  - Tabori, George (Box 38)
  - Tarlow, Rose (Box 38)
  - Taylor, John (Box 38)
  - Tchelitchew, Pavel (Box 38)
  - Tebaldi, Renata (Box 38)
  - Television (Box 38)
  - Thames, Susan (Box 39)
  - Theater-- Programs (Box 43)
  - Theater-- Programs and Playbills (Box 60)
  - Theater Hall of Fame (Box 39)
  - Thimbles (Box 39)
  - Thomas, Dylan (Box 39)
  - Thompson, Sylvia (Box 39)
  - Tiffany & Co. Table Setting (Box 39)
  - Tober, Barbara (Box 39)
  - Tobies (Box 39)
  - Todd, Michael (Box 39)
  - Tomlin, Lily (Box 39)
  - Tony Awards (Box 39)
  - Tourel, Jennie (Box 39)
  - Toys (Box 39)
  - Tree, Iris (Box 39)
  - Trilling, James (Box 39)
  - Trilling, Lionel and Diana (Box 39)
  - Truman, James (Box 39)
  - Tudor, Antony (Box 39)
  - Tynan, Kenneth and Kathleen (Box 39)
  - Udell, Rochelle (Box 39)
  - Vanderlip, Elin (Box 39)
  - Van Vechten, Carl (Box 39)
  - Vanity Fair (Box 39)
  - Vanity Fair-- Portraits and Histories, 1870s and 1880s (Box 102)
  - Venice, (2 Folders) (Box 39)
  - Viardot, Pauline (Box 39)
  - Victoria (Queen) (Box 39)
  - Vienna (Box 39)
  - Vilades, Pilar (Box 39)
  - Vogue (Box 39)
  - Volmer, Suzanne (Box 39)
  - Vreeland, Diana (Box 39)
  - Walcott, Derek (Box 40)
  - Walker, Dorothea (Box 40)
  - Warton, Meredith (Box 40)
  - Warwick, Katherine (Box 40)
  - Watches (Box 40)
  - Wayne, June (Box 40)
  - We Give You New York (Box 40)
  - Weissberger, Arnold (Box 40)
  - Welty, Eudora (Box 40)
  - West, Rebecca (Box 40)
  - Wilson, Peter (Box 40)
  - Williams, Maggie (Box 40)
  - Williams, Tennessee (Box 40)
  - Williams, William Carols (Box 40)
  - Winkelman, Anne (Box 40)
  - Wilson, Sandy (Box 40)
  - Wintour, Anna (Box 40)
  - Wise, Thomas (Box 40)
  - Wolff, Michael (Box 40)
  - Woolf, Virginia, (3 Folders) (Box 40)
  - Woman Print Order (Box 40)
  - Wright, Clifford (Box 40)
  - Wylie, Eleanor (Box 40)
  - Yorck, Ruth Landshoff (Box 40)
  - Young, Marguerite (Box 40)
  - Zandt, Pamela van (Box 40)
  - Zweigenthal, Gail (Box 40)
- Series III: Professional Files, 1922-1994
  Lerman's professional files relate to his career as an editor and writer, and contain editorial files (including, notably, those from his stint as Editor-in-Chief of Vanity Fair), office memos, articles that he wrote and research notes and manucripts related to his various book and publishing projects
  - Subseries III.1: Career and Office Files, 1935-1993
    This subseries is comprised of files related to Lerman's professional life as an editor and magazine writer. Included are files on each of the issues that he edited for Vanity Fair, as well as files related to his work as a contributing editor at Vogue. Also included are interviews with Lerman and files related to professional appearances and speaking engagements, as well as business and editorial files related to Lerman's book projects.
    - Career- General, 1942-1985 (Box 43)
    - The American Scholar, 1958
    - Awards, 1985 (Box 43)
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1944 (Box 43)
    - Books
      - General, 1939-1955 (Box 43)
      - Biography of D'Este Sisters-- Proposal and Notes, 1947, (2 Folders) (Box 43)
      - Chicago: Crossroads of American Enterprise, 1944 (edited by Lerman) (Box 43)
      - Cities of America Series, 1944-1952 (Box 43)
      - Franklin Watts Projects (Box 43)
      - Highways of the World (Box 43)
      - Leonardo da Vinci: Artist and Scientist, 1935-1944 (Box 43)
      - Michelangelo: A Renaissance Profile 1942-1954 (Box 43)
      - Memoir (unrealized), 1971 (Box 43)
      - The Museum: 100 Years of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1968-1969 (Box 43)
      - New York Around the Clock, 1959-1960 (Box 43)
      - Sotheby's Book, 1964-1973, (3 Folders) (Box 43)
      - The Victorian Reader, 1953-1957 (Box 43)
    - Book Reviewing, 1943-1989 (Box 43)
    - Caedomon Publishers, 1956 (Box 43)
    - Clippings, (4 Folders) (Box 43)
    - Dance Magazine, 1957
    - Fashion Group, The, 1967-1975 (Box 43)
    - Fashion Group of Philadelphia Tribute to Greer Garson, 1959 (Box 43)
    - Fashion Institute of Technology, 1983-1991 (Box 43)
    - Film: The Troublemaker, 1963 (Box 44)
    - Film Project: Dietrich, 1954 (Box 44)
    - Gourmet, 1984-1990 (Box 44)
    - Guggenheim Proposal (Box 44)
    - Harper's Bazaar, 1946-1948 (Box 44)
    - Hofstra College, 1971 (Box 44)
    - House and Garden, 1970s-1993
      - General, (2 Folders) (Box 44)
      - Harrington Piece-- "This Way to the Party," 1919 (Box 103)
      - Huntington Library (Box 44)
      - Shoot Notes (Box 44)
    - Interviews
      - Lerman Interview of Jan Morris for The Paris Review, 1989 (Box 44)
      - Lerman Interview of Robert Green (Box 44)
      - Lerman Interviewed by Rosemary Kent, 1974 (Box 44)
      - Lerman Interview "Why I Wear What I Wear" for GQ, 1985 (Box 44)
      - Lerman Interview regarding Antony Tudor for the Maya Deren Project, 1976 (Box 44)
      - Lerman Interviewed by Francesco Scavullo, 1977 (Box 44)
      - Lerman Interviewed by Mary Cantwell (Box 44)
      - Lerman Interviewed by Brigid Berlin regarding Van Vechten, 1970s (Box 44)
      - Lerman Interviewed by Brucy Handy on Conversation, 1986 (Box 44)
      - Lerman Interviewed by Nan Robertson on Books (Box 44)
      - Lerman on Vreeland, 1981 (Box 44)
      - "Lunch with Leo Lerman" Interview (Box 44)
      - Lerman Interviewed by Sonya Beasley for the BBC, 1976 (Box 44)
      - Lerman Interviewed by Richard Alleman, 1980 (Box 44)
      - Lerman on Restaurant Criticism (Box 44)
      - Lerman on the Sonnenberg House, 1979 (Box 44)
      - Lerman interviewed by June Weir, 1969 (Box 44)
      - Lerman Interview in Wine Magazine (Box 44)
      - Lerman Interviews, unsorted (Box 44)
      - Panel Discussion "How Beauty is Made," 1968 (Box 44)
        (Lerman moderated)
      - Interviews for June Davis Symposia (Box 44)
      - Interviews for Vogue Symposium, 1978 (Box 44)
      - Interviews for Vogue Symposium, 1982 (Box 44)
    - Lectures and Appearances, 1943-1980, (4 Folders) (Box 44)
    - Liner Notes, 1958-1959 (Box 44)
    - Mademoiselle, 1948-1972, (6 Folders) (Box 45)
    - Musical Courier, 1954-1955 (Box 45)
    - National Book Awards, 1960 (Box 45)
    - New York Philharmonic Children's Concerts Program Notes, 1951-1965 (Box 45)
    - New York Times, 1951 (Box 45)
    - The New Yorker, 1985-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 45)
    - Park East (Box 45)
    - Playbill, 1958-1987, (5 Folders) (Box 45)
      (contains editorial files for Playbill, as well as his Friends of George Spelvin newsletter and information)
    - Quotations, 1943-1993 (Box 45)
    - Radio and Television, 1943-1962 (Box 45)
    - Resumes, 1983-1994 (Box 45)
    - Saturday Review, 1942-1958 (Box 45)
    - Street & Smith, 1961 (Box 45)
    - Subsidiary Sales, 1953-1957 (Box 45)
    - Subscriptions, 1984-1992 (Box 45)
    - Teaching, 1943-1945 (Box 72)
    - Theatre
      - The Belle of Venice (Box 72)
      - Broadway, 1936-1948 (Box 72)
      - Clurman, Harold-- Tribute to (Box 72)
      - Costume Design, (2 Folders) (Box 72)
      - Costume Design (Box 102)
      - Fashion Follies, 1992, (3 Folders) (Box 72)
      - Feagin School of Dramatic Art (Box 72)
      - Grossinger's, 1935-1974 (Box 72)
      - Jane Eyre-- Notes and Manuscript of the Play, (3 Folders) (Box 72)
      - Newtown High School (Box 72)
      - Rogers, Richard-- Tribute, 1972 (Box 72)
      - Rosenthal, Jean-- Obituary, 1969 (Box 72)
    - The Tiger's Eye (Box 45)
    - Tobe-Coburn School for Fashion Careers, 1956-1979 (Box 45)
    - Tomorrow, 1942 (Box 45)
    - Travel (Box 75)
    - Vanity Fair, 1983-1984 (Box 46)
      - General Editorial Files, (2 Folders) (Box 46)
      - Story Inventories, 1983 (Box 46)
      - Memoranda
        - D. Holland to Leo Lerman, 1983-1984 (Box 46)
        - Office Memos (Box 46)
      - Ideas, Spring 1984 (Box 46)
      - Invitations (Box 46)
      - Opinion Makers (Box 46)
      - Vanity Fair Issue Files, August 1983-March 1984, (9 Folders) (Box 46)
      - Scrapbook (Box 102)
      - Published Issues, 1983 July-1984 March (Box 56)
    - Vogue (Box 46)
      - General Editorial Files, 1974-1992, (3 Folders) (Box 46)
      - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 46)
      - Telephone Messages (Box 46)
      - 100 Year Anniversary, 1991 (Box 46)
      - Australian Vogue Biennale, 1987 (Box 46)
    - Yaddo, 1946-1992 (Box 46)
    - Young People's Concerts (Box 46)
    - Telephone Messages, 1983-1993 (Box 55)
    - Office Notes, 1973-1984 (Box 55)
  - Subseries III.2: Writings, 1922-1994
    This subseries includes Lerman's own magazine and periodical writing, as well as manuscripts, drafts of unpublished material. This subseries is arranged alphabetically by publication in which articles appeared, and chronologically within that alphabetical arrangement.
    - The American Scholar (Box 47)
      - “A Passionate Self Appraisal” Review of Virginia Woolf’s ‘A Writer’s Diary’, 1954 Summer (Box 47)
      - Review of Woolf’s ‘Granite and Rainbow,’ 1958 (Box 47)
      - Review of Roger Shattuck’s ‘The Banquet Years’, 1958-1959 (Box 47)
      - Review of Mina Curtiss’ ‘Bizet and His World’, 1959 (Box 47)
    - The Atlantic Bookshelf
      - “Prelude to the Quartet,” Review (Box 47)
      - Reviews, undated (Box 47)
      - Aldington’s ‘The Duke’ and DeCoster’s ‘Glorious Adventures of Tyl Ulenspiegl’ (Box 47)
      - “The Bookshelf Museum,” 1944 (Box 47)
      - Review of S.H. Smith’s ‘Cardinal of Spain’ (Box 47)
      - Review of Morosco and Dugger’s ‘The Oracle of Broadway’ (Box 47)
      - Review of Thomas Craven’s ‘Cartoon Calvacade’ (Box 47)
      - Review of Darrell Garwood’s ‘Artist in Iowa’ (Box 47)
      - Review of Lennon’s ‘Victoria Through the Looking Glass’ (Box 47)
      - Review of Rewald’s ‘Camille Pissarro’ (Box 47)
      - Review of Zofia Kossak’s ‘Blessed are the Meek’ (Box 47)
      - Review of Pal Kelemen’s ‘Medieval American Art’ (Box 47)
      - Review of Richard A. Leonard’s “The Stream of Music” (Box 47)
    - The Atlantic Monthly
      - Review of Dane Chandos’ ‘Village of the Sun’ (Box 47)
      - “Potpourri,” July 1946 (Box 47)
      - E. H. Young’s ‘Chatterton Square’, Nov 1947 (Box 47)
    - British Vogue
      - Robert Lindsay Profile (Box 47)
      - Beatrix Miller (Box 47)
      - “The Algonquin in 100 Tender Words,” 1977 October 25 (Box 47)
    - CFDA Awards Program, 1986
      - “…on Meeting Marlene,”-- Manusript (Box 47)
      - “…on Meeting Marlene,” -- Program (Box 102)
    - Chicago Sun Book Week, D. H. Lawrence’s ‘The 1st Lady Chatterly’, 1944 April (Box 47)
    - Connoisseur Article, 1987 (Box 61)
    - Dance (Box 47)
      - Pieces Sent to R. Gottlieb (Lerman) (Box 47)
      - “Transfusion Needed: or Remarks on the Late Broadway Season,” July 1953 (theatre review) (Box 47)
      - “No Gains: Broadway ’53-‘54," 1954 June (Box 47)
      - “Dance: in the Movies,” 1954-1955, (3 Folders) (Box 47)
      - “Dance on Broadway: Season ’54-’55,” 1955 June (Box 47)
      - “Sweet and Sour ’55-’56,” 1956 July (Box 47)
      - “Dance on and off Broadway: ’56-’57,” 1957 June (Box 47)
      - “At the Theatre" Column
        - West Side Story,” 1957 November (Box 47)
        - ‘Copper and Brass’ and ‘Jamaica and Rumple’,” 1957 December (Box 47)
        - ‘The Music Man’,” 1958 January (Box 47)
        - ‘Nude with Violin, Time Remembered’,” 1958 February (Box 47)
        - “Backward Glance: Season 57-58,” 1958 July (Box 47)
        - ‘Body Beautiful,’ ‘Oh Captain,’ ‘New Girl in Town’,” 1958 March (Box 47)
        - ‘Wonderful Town’ and ‘My Fair Lady’,” 1958 April (Box 47)
        - ‘Ulysses in Nighttown’,” 1958 August (Box 47)
        - ‘Shakespeare in Conn.’ and ‘Nightcap’,” 1958 September (Box 47)
        - ‘Goldilocks’,” 1958 November (Box 47)
        - “At the Theatre: ‘La Plume de ma Tante’ and ‘The Flower Drum Song’,” 1959 January (Box 47)
        - Book Review: Agnes de Mille’s ‘And Promenade Home’, 1959 January (Box 47)
        - ‘Whoop-up’ and ‘Salad Days’,” 1959 February (Box 47)
        - ‘Fashion,’ ‘Taboo Revue,’ ‘Redhead’,” 1959 March (Box 47)
        - ‘Juno,’ ‘On the Town,’ ‘Lute Song’,” 1959 April (Box 47)
        - “Close-up of ‘Redhead’,” 1959 May (Box 47)
        - ‘First Impressions,’ ‘Destry Rides Again,’ ‘Once Upon a Mattress’,” 1959 June (Box 47)
        - Gypsy, Once Upon a Mattress (II), Destry (II), 1959 July (Box 47)
        - ‘Leave it to Jane,’ ‘The Billy Barnes Revue’,” 1959 September (Box 47)
        - ‘Happy Town’ and ‘Take me Along’,” 1959 December (Box 47)
        - 1960 January (Box 47)
        - ‘Little Mary Sunshine’,” 1960 February (Box 47)
        - “Piccolo Teatro di Milano” and “Thurber Carnival,” 1960 April (Box 47)
        - 1960 June (Box 47)
        - ‘Camino Real,’ ‘Fantasticks,’ ‘Ernest in Love,’ ‘King and I,’ ‘Grand Kabuki’,” 1960 July (Box 47)
        - 1960 December (Box 47)
        - ‘Camelot’ and ‘Do Re Mi’,” 1961 February (Box 47)
        - ‘The Happiest Girl in the World’,” 1961 May (Box 47)
        - “Carnival,” 1961 June (Box 47)
        - ‘Donney Brook’ and ‘Pal Joey’,” 1961 July (Box 47)
        - ‘Sail Away’ and ‘Milk and Honey’,” 1961 November (Box 47)
        - 1961 December (Box 47)
        - 1962 January (Box 47)
        - ‘Subways are for Sleeping,’ ‘A Family Affair,’ and ‘New Faces of 1962’,” 1962 March (Box 47)
        - ‘All American,’ ‘I Can Get it for You Wholesale,’ ‘No Strings’,” 1962 May (Box 47)
        - ‘Bravo Giouanni,’ ‘Anything Goes,’ ‘Brigadoon,’ ‘Forum’,” 1962 July (Box 47)
        - ‘Stop the World.. .’ and ‘Mr. President’,” 1962 December (Box 47)
        - ‘No Where to go but Up’ and ‘Little Me’,” 1963 January (Box 47)
        - “Lament for Broadway,” 1963 June (Box 47)
        - “Revivals Save the Day,” 1963 July (Box 47)
        - “Visit to the Antique World,” 1963 August (Box 47)
    - Dance News Annual, “Theatre Dance in My Time,” 1953 (Box 47)
    - Dance News Annual, “Theatre Dance in My Time,”-- Published Book 1953 (Box 61)
    - The Doctor’s Wife (Box 47)
      - Down the Avenue of Arts and Letters Column, 1960-1961 (Box 47)
      - “Proceed…To Theatre Pleasure” (Box 47)
    - Fantasy Furniture Afterword for Bruce Newman’s Book, 1989 (Essay) (Box 47)
    - Fledgling Flights, “Prayer of Seventeen,” 1935 (Box 47)
      (Poem)
    - (The 21st) Friendship Fete, “Profile: Carmel Snow,” 1959 March (Box 47)
    - Glamour
      - “Conversation on Culture,” 1948 April (Box 47)
      - “Conversation on Party Going,” 1948 August (Box 47)
      - “Conversation on Reading,” 1948 October (Box 47)
      - “Feet” Essay (Box 47)
    - GQ 1985 July (Box 61)
    - Gourmet
      - The Cookbook Shelf Column Manuscripts, 1984-1989, (7 Folders) (Box 48)
      - The Cookbook Shelf-- Published, 1984-1989 (Box 61)
    - Harper's Bazaar
      - "Maggie Teyte" Profile, 1935 September (Box 48)
      - "Rediscoveries: Those Backward Glances," 1945 November (Box 48)
      - "Over Seventy," 1945 December (Box 48)
      - “New York,” 1946 February (Box 48)
      - “They Saw Themselves,” 1946 March (Box 48)
      - “Hollywood: Art,” 1946 April (Box 48)
      - “The New Spirit,” 1946 April (Box 48)
      - “Rediscoveries,” 1947 December (Box 48)
      - “Living Legends,” 1948 September (Box 48)
      - “The Life and Times of Floria Tosca,” 1958 October (Box 48)
      - “Favorite Trips,” 1948 June (Box 48)
        (unpublished)
    - House and Garden
      - "The American Eye," 1946 December (Box 48)
      - "Fresh Paint," 1947 December (Box 48)
      - “Nantucket Notebook/Scrapbook,” 1948 July (Box 48)
      - “Perfect Placement,” 1986 August (Box 48)
      - “A Grand Surprise,” 1989 November (Box 48)
      - "The Legend Lives On," 1990 January (Box 48)
      - “The Social Climbing of Chairs,” 1990 December (Box 48)
      - “This Way to the Party,” 1991 August (Box 48)
      - House and Garden Published Magazines with Lerman's Writings, 1986 1989 1990 (Box 61)
    - Junior Bazaar-- "The Shouting's About" Column, 1946-1947, (13 Folders) (Box 48)
      (includes columns devoted to Bennington College, Cornell University, and Smith College)
    - Mademoiselle
      - “We American Girls,” 1950 March (Box 48)
      - “Going, Going, Gone,” 1950 July (Box 48)
      - "The Last Magic," 1950 October (Box 48)
      - “Something to Talk About: They All Discovered America,” 1951 July (Box 48)
      - “Lady Editors,” 1951 September (Box 48)
      - “Come to My Party,” 1952 March (Box 48)
      - “Escape With Us,” 1952 April (Box 48)
      - “Your Community Theatre,” 1952 June (Box 48)
      - “One Hour to Hamlet,” 1953 April-May (Box 48)
      - “The Lives and Times of Porgy and Bess,” 1953 July (Box 48)
      - “Louisville Shows Us,” 1954 May (Box 48)
      - “The Indestructibles,” 1954 June (Box 48)
      - “Diet for the Mind…,” 1954 July (Box 48)
      - “The Lives and Times of Oklahoma,” 1955 May (Box 49)
      - “The Country in the Picture Frames,” 1955 October (Box 49)
      - “Mozart’s Cradle Stoop Here,” 1955 December (Box 49)
      - “The Dutch and Us,” 1956 (Box 49)
      - “The World of 1855/56,” 1956 January (Box 49)
      - “Rubicon of 30,” 1956 January (Box 49)
      - “The Lives and Times of the Dime Novel,” 1956 January (Box 49)
      - “The Enormous Museum,” 1956 February (Box 49)
      - “The Lives and Times of Pygmalion,” 1956 December (Box 49)
      - “Point of Departure,” 1958 July (Box 49)
      - “Dallas/Callas,” 1958 October (Box 49)
      - “All Through the House,” 1958 December (Box 49)
      - “101 Days of Summer…Part and Part 2,” 1959 May-June (Box 49)
      - “The Newcomers,” 1960 January (Box 49)
      - “Castles…The Practical Dream,” 1960 March (Box 49)
      - “The Collecting Rage,” 1960 July (Box 49)
      - “Most Likely to Succeed,” 1960 September (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1960 December (Box 49)
      - “The Quality of Heart,” 1961 February (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1961 February, March, (2 Folders) (Box 49)
      - “Traveler’s Choices: Bruges,” 1961 March (Box 49)
      - “All-American,” 1961 April (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1961 March (Box 49)
      - “Something to Talk About: Athens,” 1961 May (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1961 June, 1961 October, 1962 June, (3 Folders) (Box 49)
      - “Taken by the Gypsies,” 1963 (Box 49)
      - “Christmas Gift,” 1963 December (Box 49)
      - “On Bended Knee,” 1963 February (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1963 April, 1963 September, 1964 April, 1964 May, (4 Folders) (Box 49)
      - “Group On: The Group,” 1965 September (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1965 September (Box 49)
      - “At Least 130 People in Love,” 1965 October (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1965 October (Box 49)
      - “Success,” 1965 December (Box 49)
      - “Last Minute,” 1965 December (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1965 December (Box 49)
      - “Will the Real Work of Art Please Stand Up?," 1966 January (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1966 January (Box 49)
      - “Imports,” 1966 February (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1966 February, 1966 March, (2 Folders) (Box 49)
      - “The Third Stream Off-Off Broadway,” 1966 March (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1966 June (Box 49)
      - “New York, London, Paris, Collect,” 1966 June (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1966-1967, (4 Folders) (Box 49)
      - "All Through the House," 1968 November (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1968-1971, (13 Folders) (Box 49)
      - “Ken Russell: The Case of the Sacred Monster,” 1971 November (Box 49)
      - “Catch up With,” 1972 January, 1972 March, (2 Folders) (Box 49)
      - “Who’s in Love with Louisa May Alcott? I am,” 1973 December (Box 49)
      - “Something to Talk About: On Being Young”-- A Review of Marguerite Young's Miss Macintosh, My Darling, 1973 December (Box 49)
      - “If You Can’t Travel Read” (Box 49)
      - Scrapbooks, 1949-1965 (Box 50)
      - Scrapbooks, 1966-1972 (Box 51)
      - Tear Sheets, (3 Folders) (Box 51)
    - The Museum: 100 Years and the Metropolitan Museum of Art-- Published Book (Box 61)
    - Musical Courier-- "Along 57th Street" Column, 1954-1956, (6 Folders) (Box 49)
    - The Nutcracker Ballet–Tchaikovsky, 1963 (Liner Notes) (Box 49)
    - New York Herald Tribune Weekly
      - "A Novel that Gide and Malraux Praised"-- Review of Malaquais' Men From Nowhere, 1943 (Box 49)
      - "A Real Phycho-Thriller"-- Review of Carpenter's Experiment Perilous, 1943 (Box 49)
      - “3 Quite Different Spring Novels" Review of Bowles’ Two Very Serious Ladies, 1943 April (Box 49)
      - “From Italy to Coalville, Col"--Review of Jo Pagano’s Golden Wedding, 1943 April (Box 49)
      - “Yesterdays Children and Other New Novels"-- Review of Robertson’s South From Yesterday, 1943 April (Box 49)
      - “The Art of Good Living"-- review of Wright’s The Bed-Book of Eating and Drinking, 1943 July (Box 49)
      - “Daughter of Mississippi"-- review of Welty’s Wide Net and Other Stories, 1943 September (Box 49)
      - Review of Rosamond Marshall’s Kitty, 1943 October (Box 49)
      - “A Pathetic Villain"-- review of Frances Winwar’s The Sentimentalist, 1943 December (Box 49)
      - “Novels of Backwood’s Small-Town Folks"-- review of McCoy’s Swing the Big-Eyed Rabbit, 1944 March (Box 49)
      - “Gay, Sardonic, Tense"-- review of R.L. Yorck’s Sixty To Go, 1944 March (Box 49)
      - “Reviews of New Fiction of Near’s Far"-- review of Warner’s Return of the Traveller, 1944 May (Box 49)
    - New York Post-- "As Christopher Morley Says…," 1943 (Box 49)
    - The New York Spy-- "Men's Shopping," 1966-1967 (Box 49)
    - New York Times Book Review
      - “Aztec House Opera"-- review of De Madariaga’s Heart of Jade, 1944 (Box 49)
      - “From Death to Life"-- review of Mannes’ Message from a Stranger, 1948 (Box 49)
      - “Pictures of England’s ‘Middle West’"-- review of John Moore’s Brensham Village, 1948 (Box 49)
      - “The Legend of Richard"-- review of Gore Vidal’s A Search For the King, 1950 (Box 49)
      - “The Brooding Cliffs"-- review of Margaret Kennedy’s The Feast, 1950 (Box 49)
      - “In Current Fiction: Ego, Us, Love"-- review of Helen Howe’s The Circle of the Day, 1950 (Box 49)
      - “Chronicle (from the inside out) of a Quainte English Parish"-- review of Lancaster’s They…Draynefleet, 1950 (Box 49)